Newman, Donald J.; Papers ua902.024
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Criminal Justice Projects, 1959-1983; 3; 2.0 cubic ft.
  Contains letters, proposals, and background information pertaining to various projects Dr. Newman and the School of Criminal Justice was involved in over the course of his career. Subjects include the creation of a Criminal Justice Institute, a state-wide organization (1983), Work for the Institute for Public Policy Alternatives (IPPA), 1974-75, a SUNY-institute, including "Community Alternatives to Maximum Security Institutionalization for Selected Offenders", (1975), studies of juvenile delinquency (1963-65) (includes documents dating back to 1913), and research on police and prisons (1959-1966).
  - Attica: McKay Commission, 1972 (Box 1 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 1)
  - Center for the Study of Dangerous Offenders, 1963-1966 (Box 1 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 2-3)
  - "Community Alternatives to Maximum Security Institutionalization for Selected Offenders", Final Report on the Project on; Institute for Public Policy Alternatives (IPPA), 1974-1975 (Box 1 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 4-5)
  - Corrections Bibliography - McKay Commission, 1974 (Box 1 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 6)
  - Criminal Justice Institute - Development Proposal, 1983 (Box 1 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 7)
  - Criminal Justice Institute, Committee to Create a, 1983 (Box 1 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 8)
  - Dangerous Persons Committee, 1964-1965 (Box 1 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 9)
  - Disciplinary Segregation Study - National Science Foundation, 1972 (Box 1 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 10-11)
  - Education Project in Criminal Justice, 1977-1978 (Box 1 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 12)
  - Final Report of the Training Program in Criminal Justice Education, 1977-1978 (Box 1 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 13)
  - Federal Sentencing Deskbook, 1961 (Box 1 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 14-15)
  - Institute for Public Policy (IPPA): Advisory Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 1 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 16)
  - IPPA: Bibliography, Undated (Box 1 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 17)
  - IPPA: Bi-Monthly Reports, 1974-1975 (Box 1 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 18)
  - IPPA: Correction System in New York, 1975 (Box 1 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 19)
  - IPPA: Differential Probation Projects, 1975 (Box 1 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 20)
  - IPPA: Grant, 1974-1975 (Box 1 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 21)
  - IPPA: Miscellaneous and Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 1 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 22)
  - IPPA: NY Sentencing Provisions, 1975 (Box 1 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 23)
  - IPPA: Predicate Felony Upheld, 1975 (Box 1 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 24)
  - IPPA: Preliminary Outline, 1974 (Box 1 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 25)
  - IPPA: Probation Subsidy, 1975 (Box 1 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 26)
  - IPPA: Sentencing Alternatives, 1974 (Box 1 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 27)
  - IPPA: Statistical Tables, 1975 (Box 1 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 28)
  - Juvenile Delinquency, 1963-1965 (Box 1 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 29-31)
  - Juvenile Delinquency- Historical, 1913-1969 (Box 2 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 1-3)
  - Long Term Prisoner Project, 1975 (Box 2 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 4-5)
  - Narcotics- University of Wisconsin Policy, 1967 (Box 2 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 6-7)
  - National Advisory Commission on Standards for Parole Services, 1972 (Box 2 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 8)
  - New York Prisons, 1948-1972 (Box 2 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 9-12)
  - Police, 1965-1966 (Box 2 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 13-16)
  - Prison References, 1974 (Box 2 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 17)
  - Proseminar: Criminal Justice, 1968-1970 (Box 2 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 18-19)
  - Research Committee, 1968-1969 (Box 2 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 20)
  - Standards for Correction in Criminal Justice Proposal, 1971 (Box 2 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 21)
  - Summer Seminar: Corrections Teachers, 1973 (Box 2 (3-Criminal Justice Projects), Folder 22)